What's your name?
你叫件麻名字
Mosquito
琢子
Why did those mad dogs pick on you?
那禾焦交狗干咏找你麻烦
For a chicken leg
因扁一根从腿
Huh?
蛤
Want me to go with you?
需要我陪你去吗
No
不用了
Not the first time anyway
反正又不是第一次
I can go by myself
我自己去就好了
Sorry
歹势
Three schools in two years, huh?
你十年换三个学校啊
Missed classes for half semester when you were in Grove Town
你在机宁的时候膛肪课半个学期
You been busy, huh? Lots of business going on?
你很忙哩 事业做很大哩
Nah
没有
I'm telling you,
我告诉你虽
you better behave,well
你就给我老老实实的
Don't mess around
你不要给我筷摘哩
Huh?
蛤
Uh-huh
咽
Uh-huh, what you mean by uh-huh?
嗯 嗯什么嗯
Taking shit uh-huh, huh?
大便啊嗯
Gambling, eh?
贱博啊
You've got some guts, huh?
及子倒是很大啊
Hands forward, forward
把手伸出来 伸出来
(The new guy)
(新来的)
(On the dike, tomorrow after school )
(明天放学堤防上)
(Bring NT$3000 to pay your respect)
(带3000元来拜码头)
(Or else...)
(要不然)
What the fuck
三小
Loser
俗仔
You need some beating
久打
Boss Dog Boy
狗仔孩大仔
You eat my lunch everyday
你每天都吃我的便当
My nanny says I've become too skinny
我阿娘说我太阁了叭
Too skinny?
你太关
Your nanny's blind or somethin’
你阿娘眼睛是被蛤晴肉涂到啶
What you eating that fast for?
吃这广快干嘛
Haven't paid your bill this month?
你有还没缴班费哩
It's OK, you can pay with a chicken leg
没关傈啦 缴难腿也可以啦
Collected by me, Mr. Dog Boy
我狗仔孩代收
Welcome, you're now listening to
坎迎收蒜
Mr. Lee's "Hour of Sensibility"
李季准的感性时间
This is a barbequed chicken leg from the Grove guy
这是一支来自枯林的里允腿
Don't run!
列跑
Dice go!
西巴拉
You need only five
五黑就有了叭
C'mon
来啦
Again, again
再来再来
Hit it
逼机叭
So many of them picking on one?
这广多个打一个吗
Where the hell is this fag from?
这衰尾道人哪来的啊
Just got transferred
刚夸求的
See how far you can go
我看你多会跑
Get him up
拆起来
Go ahead and run
跑啊
You fucker keep running!
你娘 你再跑啊
You run fast
你跑很快咏
Playing dumb in front of your daddy?
你给你爸装肖
Shit
带屎
What’re you doing?
你要干嘛
What about that?
那个 怎庆样
Not bad
不错啊
Where's your manners?
看到人不会打招呼啊
Scar, cigarettes
刀疤 黄
What's wrong with him?
他是哪里有问题啊
I'll tend to your wound in a minute
等下来攻你控药
Scar
刀疤
Sister Ling
小玲姐
What's this for, no
这干嘛 不要叭
You have already sent so many flower banquets
之前都已经送那广多花篮来了
You also spent quite a lot when you took over the business
你顶这家店也花了不少炙
How could you say no to my cash gift ?
礼金怎麻能不收
Bye, Sister Ling
小玲姐再见
Pay 50 bucks to get through
通路费五十块
Want to be friends?
要交个朋友呆
Fuck off
了网啦
Did you get that chick yesterday?
你昨天马子有到手吗
She ran away
被她跑了只
Loser
没用
I beat up the newbie
我打新来的
what's that to do with you Temple Front?
趴你们扁口有什么其傈啊
Excuse me, Mr. Boss Dog Boy
歹势虽 狗仔孩大何
Just a notice
通知你一声
From now on, his business is my business
从现在开始他的事就是我的事
His enemy, is my enemy
他的做人就是我的仇人
Whatever people owes him
列人入他的
I'll get it back for him
我一定会帮他言回来
Whatever he doesn't want from people
别人送他他不要的
I will give it back for him
我一定会帮他还回去
Would you please tell me
请问一下
Did you pick on him yesterday?
你昨天是不是有找他麻烦
Dragon Lee
李上志龙
Don't pick on me
你不要趁我堂哥进去蹲的时候
when my cousin is in jail
找藉口弄我虽
Pick on you
找藉口再你
Just like you called up those body builders to pick on him yesterday?
就像你昨天找那群健美先生弄他啊
Making him pay respect, huh?
拜码头
This is your turf, huh?
这跟是你码头哩
Now, nobody is picking on anybody
现在没人查找藉口
Now I am asking you, fair and square
现在是光明正大请冉你
Did you pick on him yesterday?
你昨天是不是有找他麻烦
How nice, everyone's here
很好 全员到珊
I, Dragon Lee, is here, no one dares to hit back, so be my guest
我李志龙在 没人节有还手 你亿量只
Do me a favor, the new guy
你也拜旗一下 这位新同学
Can you make it quick, 10 minutes have passed
要打就乾脆一蜗 都已经过了十分钙
You don't really need that much thinking
内心戏不用演这魔久吧
If you don't fuck'em up today
今天你要是不弄死他们
One day they'll fuck you up
有一天你就会被他们和弄死
My name is Chou Yi-Mong, friends call me Mosquito
我叫周以文 绰获蚊子
I moved to Monga when I was 17
在十七起那一年搬到盘租
l became a gangster, because of a chicken leg
因遍一根从腿 踏入黑道
All this fighting, is there a meaning to it?
每天这样打打届
What the fuck is meaning?
意义是三小
Your daddy only know brotherhood, never heard of meaning
你和爸只骨通义气 没划过意义只
Since I was little, l had no father, no friends
我从小没有父观 没有朋友
l was bullied by all the neighbors and kids
被痢居同学一路其负到大
Until 1 met my brothers
直到遇见了这群兄弟
My life seemed to have some meaning
我的生命好像才有了意义
No
不
What the fuck is meaning?
意义是三小
All 1 know, is brotherhood
我只知道义气
Dragon Lee
李上志龙
The only son of Geta, the boss of Monga Temple Front
艇和解祖师遍扇口老大Geta的独生子
A street prince born with a silver spoon
是个含著金汤是出生的全客太子
As the son of a gangster boss
身遍大哥的儿子
Naturally
他自然而然
all the kids respect him as the big brother
也被小朋友们当成大哥
Since he's little
从小他就是
he's been the gangster force on campus, maintaining the orders
校园里维持秩序的黑道势力
So much so, that the word Brotherhood, in his definition
以致代他理解的义气
Has everything to do with Power
四权力雨个字 脱节不了关傈
( Protection fee, 500 )
(保护费 五百)
However, the one who really has what it takes to be a boss, is him
不遇站正有大哥实力的是他
Monk, real name Ho Tien-Yo
和尚 本名何天估
When he's 5, a fortune-teller
五茂时算命的铁口直断
determined that this kid was to become a gangster
这小孩是兄弟命
( Your boy is destined to be a gangster )
(你这个孩子 将来是兄弟命)
His dad therefore asked his best friend Geta to look after him
放是他老和爸便把他托付给好友Geta
Monk is extremely intelligent
和尚台明绝顶
Showed amazing talent as early as in elementary school
小学时期便展现敬人才革
He can finish test papers for 4 people at once
他一次考试可以写四个人的考卷
Each year, he won six championships at school:
而且每一年都拿下全校
writing, speech, reading, spelling
作文 演讲 朗读 查字典
( Boss, the high mountain tea you ordered is here )
(老癌 你订的高山茶来了)
Because he has high IQ, and he's resourceful and well-mannered
由评智商很高 又知书达礼
Comparing to any of us
和尚办起事来
Monk does everything with more ease and professionalism
比我们任何一个都去用专业
Growing up with Dragon
因扁从小味志龙一起长大
Monk only cares for Dragon
和尚眼里只有志能
The way I see it
在我看来
Incomprehensible to others
外人准以理解
A-Po, Huang Wan-Po
阿伯 黄商伯
An underdog who knows best about survival
一个最懂得生存之道的俗仔
(I've been a butcher all my life )
(你爸猪儿一草子)
( How come my son is such a coward? )
(怎麻生出你这麻没脆的儿子啊)
He claims that he's killed 233 pigs
他声称自己曾经角遇 责百三十三焦猪
Done 107 women
过通一百零七个女人
Kicked 375 people's asses
打指三百七十五人
(376,379... )
(三百七十六 三百七十九)
Brotherhood for him, is a means to hustle around
义所对他求说 是招的行骗的工具
A truth only idiots would buy into
是白狼才会相信的站理
The idiot A-Po refers to
阿伯口中的白疼
Would be Monkey
指的应该就是白猴了
Monkey, real name Hou Chun-Sheng
白猴 本名候春生
His dad died soon after he was born
出生没多久他和爸就死了
His mom ran away with some man (On my white horse )
他妈味人跑了 (我身骑白马)
His grandpa raised him
他被阿公一手带大
( Through three territories )
(走三天)
( This is my line, who the heck are you? )
(这名是我要唱的 你是维)
(lam Chun-Sheng )
(我是春生啊)
Just like me
四我一样
Monkey was often bullied as a kid
白猴从小常被欺负
What's different is
不同的是
When he turned 10
他在十蕊那一年
He Suddenly realized that he was good at fighting
突然发现自己很会打
Since then, he's the one beating people up
从此只有他打别人
No one can hit him
没有别人打他的份
It was in the same year
也就在那一年
That Dragon recruited him, and he became a gangster kid
他被志龙相中 成遍一名小流襄
I took on three all by myself
刚才我一个打三个
You're talking shit
我孤你在踊烟
The highest record we ever made
我们阅下的最属纪好
was to pick up a mass fight among all gangs in Monga
是引起艇筋地区所有和角头的大拓堵
It was that night
那个晚上
that five of us became sworn brothers
也是我们五个人结拜
and formed the Prince Gang
组成太子帮的日子
Were not born on the same day
不能同年同月同日生
But are willing to die on the same day
但愿同年同月同日死
Shall anyone think twice, will be punished by the Master God of Monga
如有二心 屯受祖师繁全昼
To have the limbs broken and die an ugly death
斯手斯脚 不得好死
Hey. What do you want to do the most in life?
约 你这草子最想做的事是什么
Join the gang, be the boss
混黑道 当大哥
You wanna replace me?
你想自位啶
If 1 become the boss, then you'll be the boss's boss
我如果当大哥 你就是大可的大哥
Sweet talker
算你会说话
What if you ain't in the gang?
那如果不混啊
If Monk wasn't a gangster
和尚不混的话
he could get a PhD and win Nobel prize
可以念个博士 拿个诺具震奖
Anyway he's gotta be someone big lah
反正一定是很属害的人哗
If 1 ain't in the gang, what would I be?
我不混的话 会是什和广人
Eighteen Copper Men conquer the world with Shaolin Kung-Fu
十入铀人 少林武功著天下
Famous traditional kung-fu medicine
出名传统武功玩
Go back to sleep
睡你的啦
What about you, what you wanna do the most?
那你啊 你最想做的事是什么
Me, I wanna go to Japan
我虽 我想去日本
And do what?
做件广
Go see the cherry blossoms
看樱花
So “romantico”
很“烟漫”喧
My dad sent home a postcard from Japan before he died
我爸死前从日本案了一张明信片
On it, there's cherry blossoms all over the sky
那上面印了满天的栅花
He got passed on some kind of disease two months after he got there
他才去日本两个月就得了传汪病
He probably died not even
可能连我的存在都还不知道
knowing I was born
就丰准子了
Have you ever seen cherry blossoms?
你们看过枫花鄙
Look, cherry blossom
笋 樱花啦
Here, to your dad
来啦 数你从
Pee, of course
当然是尿啊
Bitch, asshole
你很贱 度烟效
You can't get me, won't get me
打不到打不到
Don't go.
列走
Thanks
谢啦
Hey
效
What you had was broken
蓝的那个壕了吧
Got you a new one
送你一个新的
Takin’ off
走了
Not sleeping yet?
膛没睡啊
What's going on?
发生什么事了呆
How's school?
学校最近膛好呆
Ok, nothing special
膛好啊 没有什广特别的啊
I've never asked you to get good grades
我从来没有要求你书要念得多好
All l want is that you graduate
只要你村业
Graduate from high school, that's it
高中检业就好了
Is that too much to ask?
这样要求有很遇分吗
You hang out
你是不是每天
with the Temple Front hooligans all the time?
都球衣口的小混混混在一起
Will there be a future for you sticking with them?
四他们混有前途吗
There's no such thing as future for someone like me
我这种人本来就没什么前途
Say that again
你再说一次
I wouldn't have survived school
如果不是他们覃我
if they didn't watch my back
我在学校根本混不下去
You don't steal, rob, or do anything unspeakable,
你没偷 没抢 没做鹿心事
why do you need them to protect you?
干咏要他们晶你才混得下去
What about you? Aren't you doing the same thing?
那你呢 你自己还不是一样
We just moved here, and you already hooked up with the Mainlanders
刚搬来没多久就找了外省帮求
What kind of mindset's that?
你这什广心态啊
Don't you also need someone to watch your back?
你还不是一样
We're sworn brothers now
我已经划他们结拜了
I never had any friends since I was little
从小到大我没有交遇什麻朋友
This is the first time
这是第一次
Happy birthday
生日快乐
How do you know it's my birthday?
你们怎广知道我生日
I have my way to find out
想要知道就会知道啊
Let's go celebrate
走 替你订生
Move it
走哟
How's it?
怎广样
Take a look
看看
Not bad huh, do you like it?
不错啊 喜欢咽
Thanks
谢啦
Dragon, big bro
志衣 志允
Come, come. Come on in
来来来 和里面 里面
Woo-hoo! Love birds
吻 钨爱
Get lost
了网啦
Ignore them
不要理他们
Mosquito, Mosquito
琢子 驱子
Drink up
喝啦
l'll puke if I drink more
再喝我会旺
Are we brothers or not?
是不是兄弟
Monk, Mosquito, come on, dance
和尚 蚊子 快黑 来跳啦
Hurry up
快只
Get movin'
快昧啦
Monkey
白猴
Dance with them
去跳啊
No, I can't dance
我不会
Hate, love, commotion in my heart
恨 爱 心中激动
This trap, trap, trap, why me?
这陷阱 这陷阱 这陷阱 偏我遇上
Hey, isn't it time to give our b-day boy the present?
是不是该送再星大礼啦
Mosquito
琢子
Aren't we going to get some squid soup?
不是说要去吃鲈鱼疼
Let's have it to go, you go get it
买回去吃好了啦 你去买
Oh
喧
Remember to tell the owner it's for the Temple Front
记得跟老阅说是遍口要的哩
This way he'll add extra squid, hear me?
这样他会加料 贩到没
OK
好
Hi, 5 squid soups to go, it's for the Temple Front
老问 五碗鲈急妆带走 裔口要的
Five to go, for the Temple Front
五碗带走 遍口要的
Temple Front
遍口的
Damn Temple Front, don't run! Knock him dead!
死扁口的 列跑 给他死
Don't run!
列跑
Temple Front! Get him!
遍口的 快拆起来
Don't go
列走
Kill him!
打死他
Wow, they're coming, coming, coming
哇 来了来了来了
Wow, super fast, 9 minutes 35 seconds
哇塞 超快 九分三十五秒
Mosquito
琢子
Hey, sorry about the squid soups
歹势虽 刚那拥色羡
Should I go get them again?
要不要再去买啊
Get them again?
再去丑
What you laughing about?
你们是在笑什麻
Jeez, you're unbelievable
吗 你站的很天县耶
You almost got killed
兰黑被人家打死
and you're going back there again?
你还要再去圈
Hey Monk, enlighten him
和尚 你快给他开示一下
Monga, Since the Ching Dynasty to the Japanese Era
艇和解从清朝到日据时代
has always been the busiest commercial center of Taipei
一直都是台北最热关的商业中心
It's like a gold mountain
这壬就像是一座金山
full of opportunities and dreams
充满了商机味萝想
In places like this, all kinds of people mixing together
像这样的地方 龙蛇打处
Someone needs to maintain
需要有人来维持地方秩序
the order and allocate the interests
维迟利益分配
That's where a "Block Boss" steps in
角头就是扮演这样的角色
The streets and lanes are their borders
利用街道意弄刘清界乡
Each takes care of things big and small on his own turf
各自处理自己地盘壬的大小事
Each protects the civilians on his turf
各自保访自己地盘里的老百姓
Some say there are
有人说现在艇和解地区的角头
over 70 block bosses in Monga
有七十多个
And some say over 30
也有人说是三十竹个
But no one knows
但站正的数字
for sure the actual number
从来没有人搞得清楚
Haven't you been asking
你不是一直在问
why we fight all the time?
高什么要打打条的吗
You get it now?
现在了解了吗
Boss Dragon
志龙大仔
Anywhere in Monga
反正在秀解
mention Dragon's dad's name
只要报志龙他和爸的名性
No one dares to touch you
就没人敢动你
Because we, the Temple Front, are Monga's most powerful
因遍我们遍口是最大势力
If you run into those from the Back Alley,
如果遇到和后辟层的
No need to say anything, just hit 'em
不用庆话 打就对了
Didn't we kick their ass the other day?
就我们之前撮平的那些吕
And also those at the night market tonight
还有今天在夜市里的啊
Dragon Bro
志龙大仔
Have a cigarette
抽区抽英
No I'm good
不用了
Give it to others
给和后面的
Hey Dragon, what's your dad's name?
志龙 你爸叫什么名字啊
Didn't I just tell you, Geta (Wooden clogs)
刚才不是讲通了哮 叫Geta啊
The one that shielded off the sword with two clogs
就是呈一声用木展夹武士刀那一个啊
Hey Dragon, your dad is really cool
上亏 你苞很钟耶
Hi, good day, good day
你好 你好 你好
Boss Geta
Geta大他
Come here, eat
来来来 吃饭 吃颌
Time to eat lah
吃秘足 吃据只
Lazy dude shits and pees a lot
吗 丹人屎尿多
You use the toilet whenever it's time to eat
每次要吃饭就要蹲痪所
My belly hurts, what can I do?
就胜子痛 有什么办法
Hey your kid is big
小孩大了只
you should go and register
去结一结户口报一报啦
She wouldn't marry me
她就不婷给我啊
Come on, meal time
吃舌了 吃和饭了
The kitchen ceiling is still leaking
肩房天花板膛在漏水
what did you do to fix it?
你匀是怎魔修理的啊
Look
我球你训
Tomorrow,
明天我要是进肩房炒菜
You'll be the one that's leaking
我就把你风乾滴水
Ok, ok, take a break
好啦 好啦 休息了
clean up and eat
东西收一收起来吃和饭了
Wow, braised pork
红烧肉耶
Oi, watch out for the hygiene, not with your hands
减效罗 本生一昨 不要用手拿
Come and eat
吃饭了
Come on, eat lah
来 吃啦 吃只
Is this the way of the gangster? Not exactly what I imagined
这是黑道吗 跟我想的不一样
This, is the real Taiwanese gangster
这才是正港的台湾黑道
Vulgar and powerful
俗锌有力
Ma'am
嫂子
Mom
妈
No, I'm good, you go ahead
不用 不用 你吃
Get you some rice?
要玫你添狐吗
No, l am fed up
不用啦 气包了
I just lost 16,000
刚才美枝那个三八靶
to that Mei-ji bitch
启了我一茵六
If 1 don't get it back next time along with the interest
下次要是不给她
I'll write my name backwards
你祖妈名字就给他倒遇求窟
Mon, this is my sworn brother, Mosquito
妈 这我换帖的 蚊子
Hi there
你好
Alright, you guys carry on
好只 你们继续吃
Boss, it's taken care of
大仔 我处理好了
How'd it go?
有怎样呆
Kept wailing
唉唉叫
Ok lah, go sit down and eat
好啦 坐下吃锯吧
Have a seat
坐
Riot at the Rocky Bay Prison
岩湾监狱暴动
They even sent in the SWAT team
膛派特种部队
It's turned into such a big deal
事情于这广大
Take some of this
吃菜啊
This reduces your internal heat, have some
天气热吃这个最退火 来来来
Get some more
夹多一可啦
Dad you're home
和爸 你回来吧
You were saying
你刚才说
Wim-Kian's uncle
文襄他阿披
Uh-huh
咽
Which uncle is it?
是哪一个阿投啊
Well it's Dog Boy's dad
就狗仔孩他区
Oh, Doggy
喧 阿狗喧
Wim-Kian is raised by Doggy
文训是阿狗和从小养大的
He'll get even for sure
这件事 他一定会诗回来
You better watch out
你要小心野
Boss
大体
Uncle lost 200 grand at the Temple Front bookie
阿披碍扇口的脆场输二十多菌
He told them
他中对方说
to collect from you when you come out
等你出来后再来跟你收
But they insisted on chopping down one of his fingers
但是将方坚持
Fuck
干
What you doing?
你干什往
Hey where the hell are we going?
效 我们到底要去哪里啊
Just chill, you'll know in a minute
别急只 等下你就知道了
Where's Monk?
那和尚喝
Boss Dragon
志龙大仔
There's no way he'd come for this
这种找他他也不食来足
He's not interested in women
他半女人没愉趣啦
Try saying that to him next time if you got the balls
你有种下次在他面前说说看
It is true
本来就是
He is Monk
他是和尚耶
a monk should be vegetarian and celibate
和尚都嘛要吃素 还要守色戒
Exquisite Tower
玲琅塔 塔玲琅
Tower is exquisite, there are 13 stories in the Tower
玲玩赛塔十三层
A temple in front of the Tower, an old monk in the temple
塔前有座遍 扇里有老伴
The old monk is the Master of six pupils
老僧当方丈 徒弟有六名
See?
有没有
Auntie has prepared
阿姨哩
swallow nests and shark fins for you
慈窗急翅早就帮你们淮人备好了
Pick one you like and enjoy the tonic
赶快选一个中意的进去进补
Feed yourself well, so you'll be strong
吃鲍饮 身体才会勇健
Auntie, my dad doesn't let me come to Treasure Borough,
阿姨 我爸不准我来赛斗里
you know that right?
你知道吧
I know lah
我知道啦
Cow Dung
牛屎
Yes ma'am
是
No one knows
志龙大仔来这的事
Boss Dragon was here, got it?
不准给我说出去哩
I know lah
知道啦
Auntie, get him a good one
阿姨 一定要帮他找个避的虽
my treat
我招待
Little handsome, come, your turn
小负哥 来 换你了
Wait, I'll wait, they go first
我等 我等一下 他 他们先
First timer, huh?
第一次吗
Auntie will get you a pretty one in a minute
阿姨等下帮你找一个漂亮的
Make you lose your virginity tonight
今天让你破身
Then take a red envelope for good luck
顺便带一个红包走
Auntie come in for a second
阿姨 进来一下喧
Take your pick
自己挑吗
You scared the shit out of me
你要嘛死人嘱
Auntie, how can you sell this kind of product?
阿姨 这款的你也敢拿出来
What you lookin’ at?
看什广看
I'll dig your eyes out
再看把你眼睛挖出来
Her, I can do with her
她 我可以
Did you go to Show Shang Elementary School?
你是不是秀山国小的
Didn't you always carry your lunchbox
你小时候是不是都提闭
in a washing powder bag?
一个白兰洗衣粉的袋子装便当
You're confusing me with someone else
你认错人了
You
你
Why do you want to be a hooker?
你高什么要做妓女啊
What about you?
那你呢
Why do you want to be a gangster?
你高什么要做兄弟
Can we talk first?
可不可以先聊天
What's your name?
你叫件广名字啊
Whatever
随便
I'm Mosquito
我叫蚊子
Music?
你要匠咽
Whatever
随便
Thanks, come again
谢谢 再来
Hey
效
My name is Ning
我叫小且
Oh
喧
Stop pouting
你不要再庆了叭
I'm not pouting
我哪有上处
If you wanna see "Fatal Attraction"
你要看致命的吸引力
we can do it next time
我下次再陪你去看嘛
How was it?
怎广样
How was what?
件广怎庆样
Was it good?
更不爽啊
With that birthmark girl yesterday
昨天吐那个胎记妹
No
我不管
None of your business
天你屁事啊
I don't want next time. l wanna see it today
我不要下次 我就是要今天
Hey what's the fuss about?
效 在吵什入
Everybody wants to see this one
我们大家都是要看这部嘛
Everybody, everybody. It's everybody again.
大家 大家 又是大家
No idea
不知道
Fuck, mad woman
干 普婆
What do you want? Picking on me or what?
你现在是怎样 找我麻烦是不是
lam not picking on you
我没有找你麻烦
If only you did what you promised
你说到做到就好了啊
The "Project A" sequel is what ! wanna see
我就是要看A计画续集只
If you don't like it, then leave
不更看就走啊
Excuse me, I am Dragon's friend
歹势 我是志龙的朋友
You guys had a fight?
你们吵架了喧
He asked me to come look for you
他叫我来找你叭
He wants to apologize
他想中你道火
He didn't earlier
刚刚因高有其他人碍
because the other guys were there
他不方便说什和
You understand, right?
你应该懂吧
Men don't like to look bad in front of friends
男人都爱面子咏
He asked me to come get you
他叫我带你进去找他
He's waiting for you in the back
他在后面等你啦
Come this way, in the back
求 这录 和后面
This way
求 在这下
In the back
在后面
I just wanted to enjoy a movie with him
我只是想味他好好看一场志影
And he invited those guys again
他就又找那群人来
I don't understand
监的很莫名其妙
Why does he have to be like this all the time?
高什么每一次都要这样
He's in the back
他在后面
You know why?
你知道扁什么吗
Because Dragon Lee is a freakin’ fag
因扁李志龙是个臭俗仔哗
Without those guys around all the time
他穷下如果没有吐一堆人的话
He'd be scared shitless
他会嘛到尿裤子
You got me?
懂了吗
Shush
安表
Hey
效
Gotta go
那我先走了
See you tomorrow
明天网
Have you seen Hui?
你有看到小惠吗
Fuck, you're shitting me
看 我匠你在放屁啊
Boss, I am not lying
大仔 我没有骗你
that chick is real hot
那个女的站的很漂亮啦
Show me tomorrow then
那明天带我去啊
Sure, I'll take you tomorrow
好 明天带你去
I have no idea what you're saying
我节不懂你们在说什启
I didn't do anything
我又没怎样
Didn't do anything?
没怎样
Then why did you run?
没怎样看到我们干嘛跑
Gimme a break, you guys got weapons
拜旗 你们拿停伙敢
Who wouldn't run when they see you?
谁看到不会跑啊
Who knows, maybe the Prince Gang is just
谁知道是不是你们太子帮手瘘
itching to beat someone up
又想有要妃岳人啊
Fuck, you're full of shit
干 你理由很多嘛
A man is responsible for his actions
男子汉敢做敢当
How come there's such garbage like you?
世间怎广会有你这种垃级
I didn't do nothing
没有就是没有啊
I'm being framed
你们不要证太我好不好
Some fucking bitch set me up
干 到庶哪一个臭嫩子在整我啊
Shut his mouth
把他嘴封起来
Hey you can't be serious
笋 你们不是认凌的吧
To be a man is to be serious
做人 就是要认昌
First, I will seal your mouth
等一下我会先把你的跨封起来
And then left eye
然后左眼
Then right eye
右眼
Left ear
左耳
Right ear
右耳
Left nostril
左引孔
Then drive you into the mountains
然后把你载到山上
Dig a hole, throw you in there
挖个洞丢进去
Pour in vitriol, and then fill up the hole
最后倒昨酸理起来
Monk, you can't do this
和尚 你不能这样
What you gonna say to my cousin?
你人这样 你怎广味我堂可交代
Why do I have to explain to Wim-Kian?
我扁什么要大文训交代
I don't belong to the Back Alley, lam from the Temple Front
我不是后慰计的 我遍口的耶
Are you fucked up in the head?
你头珊壤去了哩
Besides, having done something like that
而且你做出这种事情
You are the one
你才要想想看
who should figure out what to say to Wim-Kian
你要怎广半文襄交代
Stay away from me
你不要过来喔
What the fuck, what the fuck are you doing?
你要干什麻 你要干什么
Fuck, what you doing
干 你要干什么
Seal it
封起来
Seal his mouth
把他嘴封起来
Fuck, don't fuck with me
干 你不要妃来吕你
What the fuck
别病骂 你不要妃来喔
Seal the eyes
封眼睛
Dragon, Dragon
志衣 志允
Fuck, let go of me
干 你把我放开
Let go of me
你把我放并啦
He fucked my woman, don't you know that?
他弄的是我的女人你知不知道
He fucked my Hui
他和弄的是小惠啊
I'll do it
我来
Hey
效
No need to worry
不用担心啦
I'll take him to the doc I know he'll fix it
我明天会带他去
It'll be alright
没事的
Thank you, see you again
要再来耶 慢走
Thanks
谢谢
Auntie, I want Ning
阿姨 我找小凝
Ning is with a customer at the moment
小凝现在有客人耶
I'll get you a prettier one
不然我帮你找一个更漂亮的
Hey A-mei
嘿 阿梅啊
It's ok, I'll wait
不用 我等
So faithful
这广疾情喔
Handsome, come in, don't go away
钟可 进来嘛 不要走嘛
Come again soon
有空再来喔
Who did this?
谁打你
If I collect less than 30 cards
做不到三十支租
One whip for one card short
少一支抽一鞠
Sorry
对不起
What you sorry for
干咏圣不起
You didn't turn me into this
我会变成这样 又不是你害的
What's up with you?
你发生什往事啊
Can I spend the night here?
我今天可以睡这壬吗
How many more do you need? I'll buy them all
膛差路支我全买了
I bought a lot
我买了很多
Even one for Dog Boy
也有圈给狗仔孩的
Sorry, I forgot that he can't eat
歹势 我访了他不能吃
Didn't you say it's no problem?
不是说没问题的咽
Could be too much in the nose
可能是引子灌太多了
Oi
效
Where is it?
球啊
What?
件广
The yo-yo
溜溜球
The five of you, try to fly
你们五个 翅膀膛没乾
when you still don't know how to walk?
就会起了
Blackie and I only went to the South for a couple of days
我跟黑面不过去南部两天而已
You already made such a big mess
竞然到惹出这魔大的事情
When the day comes that I'm gone
要是哪一天我不在了
Would that mean the end of Temple Front?
遍口不就要收起来了
The Prince Gang my ass
什订太子才
Lost your mind for a Mainlander chick
竟然遍了一个外省婆子失去了理智
Dragon Lee, you really think you're a prince?
李啊志龙 你览的以扁你是太子鄙
man's life is worth nothing for you?
人命查你眼睛和里 览的不值袋呆
You can kill when you can't even kneel properly?
连跷都跑不好 膛会儿人啊
Look, if you fall again
我跟你说吕 你再给我跌倒
I'll beat you to death
我就打死你
I'll be your page boy if I don't
要不然 换我做你小弟
Boss, I made this mess
大仔 这件事是我车出求的
It's got nothing to do with them
趴他们四个没有关傈
It's all my fault
都是我不好
Fine, get up
好 起来
All get up!
都起来啦
You are good
你站行啊
I wouldn't know if you didn't tell me
你不说我都不知道
It's your fault
是你不兰啦
It has nothing to do with them
聚他们四个都没关傈啦
You are good
你很行啊
How come you're so good?
你怎广这麻行
So good
这麻行
You are really good
你站行啊
Dad
区
You
你
Heading back?
要回去啦
Uh-huh
咽
Boss Masa
Masa大仔
He almost wasted him. God forbid
打成人这样 天毒
He meant to kill him or what?
这是存心想要他的命
When kids make a mistake, they should be disciplined
小孩子做错事 是该教训一下
You haven't changed a bit, so naive
你到现在还这麻天疾
Don't you know what kind of person he is?
那像炙是哪种人你不知道
Sigh...
唉
We're brothers for so many years
大家兄弟做这魔多年了
We're like family
狗是有感情
Family? If only he felt the same way, too
有感情 有感情就没道义只
Secretly hired someone
暗中叫人简了你的手
to chop off your hand, and took your place
膛估你的位来举
And now, he fucked up your son when he got the chance
现在找到机会
Don't talk about this in front of the kid
不要在小孩面前说这些话
Come, come outside
来 来外面
Hey, why aren't you sleeping? What's going on?
你不睡 起来做件麻
What he just said, is it true?
他说的是事实吗
Chou Ling-Wan, your registered mail
周玲婉指呈
Oh
喧
Be right back
等我一下虽
I'm takin’ off
我走唆
Got enough money with you?
仅带得金不锡
Yeah
锡
Careful
小心咀
I will
会啦
Sorry about that
不好意思哩
No worries
不会
Your son is very good-looking, going out?
你儿子好钟吗 要出去玩啊
Yeah
雪
Pre-graduation trip
去毕业旅行啦
He's graduating?
都要录业唆
You are really lucky
你站是好命虽
You're too kind
哪有
Sweeping Blade
择刀
Stabbing tube
征管
Samurai 8-feet
尺八
Samurai 2-feet
尺二
Edged stiletto
扁氏
Whenever you have time,
你们要是有空的时候
take them out, feel them and clean them
就拿出来摸一摸擦一控
Befriend them
交个朋友
When you are in trouble
你们要是有困难的时候
Your friends will support you
朋友才会相挺
Get it?
知道吗
Hurry up, you're falling behind
和后面的快一骂
Son of a bitch, fuck
干你娘 干
One, two, three
一 一二
Hey, I just took a piss
效 我小便耶
What age is it ?
什和广时代了
They all use guns now
现在都是拿抢
What's the point of practicing these?
张这些有什麻用啊
Come on, when the guns are loaded
拜论 人家枪都拔出来
Do we have the time to turn around and get our 2-feet, 8-feet?
哪膛有时间转头拿什么尺二尺八
Our asses are already getting shot at
屁股都并花了叭
What the fuck did you say?
就什启
Boss Geta
Geta大他
Dad
区
Boss
大体
Guns are evil things imported from the West
枪是西方人所传来的邪恶东西
They are for those who don't have balls
是没种的人在用的
Weapon for the lowly
是下等人的武器
To establish oneself in the underground society
黑社会中打滚
One depends on his fists and knives
就要靠源头 靠刀
I won't let the five of you lay your hands on guns
我不准你多五个碰枪
You hear me?
匠到没
Yes
有
Let's go
下山哗
Take your shit and let's go
东西收收下山中
Yay! The training camp is over!
耶 魔鬼训张和营结束啦
Black Dog Bro on the mountain top
山顶一个黑狗兄
He is the young master of the ranch
伊是牧场的少繁
Hard working night and day
造早到暗览打拼
His huge ranch takes up the whole mountain
禾场并阅整山评
His singing is loud and cheerful
嘴叭明朗的歌声
He sings non-stop all day long
造日歌声叭不停
His songs are so beautiful
伊的歌疙站好骸
His nice singing voice got him famous
声好会叭盖出名
l hear his voice but can't see him, yo le yi li
有匠声 看扰影 估鹃伊哩
Throughout the whole mountain there is his voice, yo le yi li
歌读玮山筑 您啊伊哩
The voice is pure and lovely, yo le yi li
歌声幼嫩缘投得人头 悠啊伊哩
Yo le yi, yo le yi li
您明伊 您明伊哩
Thank you
谢谢
Applause please
掌声鼓励一下
Boss, what an incredible night
大仔 天在下红雨唾
Both bosses of Monga Temple Front
你们艇和解遍口趴后辟层的老大
and Back Alley are here
都来这挤场耶
Masa is here?
Masa有来喔
Yeah
有啊
Good, I'll go have a drink with him later
那好 等下我找他喝一杯
Sure, sure
好啊 好啊
Hey
效
aren't the Back Alley guys our enemies?
我们不是味后壁层的势不责立咽
Of course
兰啊
Then why Boss Geta said he'd go drink with the boss of Back Alley?
那扁什么刚Geta大仔 说要跟后慰层的老大喝一杯
Oh, they are buddies
吗 他人匀是麻吉啊
They are buddies?
他们是麻吉
Uh-huh
咽
They were sworn brothers
他们当初也是有结拜的啊
Like the five of us
就跟我们五个一样
One day you'll get your own block, I'll have mine
以后你有你的角闫 我有我的地盘
Our subordinates fight when they see each other
底下的人见到就打
But for us on the top, when we meet
但我们当大哥的碰到
having a drink is a must
喝一杯是一定要的
You'd better watch out
你以后小心一时啊
I'm not scared of you
没查怕的啦
If you don't tell what's on your mind
心事若扰讲出来
Who will ever know?
有谁人会知
Sometimes I really want to
有时联想要诉出
Stepped into the underground
踏入七逃界
1 shouldn't have
是阮不应该
Now that I want to undo my mistakes
如今想反悔
Who would understand?
谁人篆诗解
My love if you know my heart...
心爱你若有隘解
Hey, homeboy, what a coincidence
丝 兄弟 这魔刚好
l was about to go have a drink with you
正想找你喝一杯说
Who you with?
你味谁来
Wim-Kian, he just got out
文襄路 刚出来
Came to welcome him back
才他接风一下
How long was he in there?
天多久
House Cleaning Operation, it's been three years
一清 三年虽
Three years already
三年有了
He brought a Mainlander with him
他带了一个外省的来
Said the Mainlander took care of him in there
说是在里面很照顾他
Brought him to introduce to us
带来认识一下
Lately I heard those Mainlanders
册说他们那些外省的
want a piece of Monga
最近想来我们艇和解估地盘
Oh, gimme a break, don't think too much
约哆 拜旗啦 不要在那录筷想叭
I can't even speak "Mandorin"
我速“狗语”都说不好了
With them, there is nothing we can talk about
四他们有件麻好这拼的
Hey homeboy, I'm thinking, seriously
兄弟 我想距 讲站的啦
Couple of events happened to Wim-Kian’s household
文误他们家壬这化件事情
If you can, would you come and say hello?
方便的话 你要不要打声招呼
His uncle cheated in games, I handled it by the book
他阿披诈腾 我是照规托来
His cousin raped a woman
那他堂弟之前强圳一个女人
I sorted it out for him, too
我也替他解决啦
The street, and business, the rules, I did everything right
黑白雨道 江湖道义 我都有顾啊
Why should I apologize
高了这种事情
to a youngster for things like these?
膛要我去跟一个小弟解释喝
Nah, you know it
不是 你也知道
Wim-Kian is like a mad dog
文廊这个人 就像一焦站狗
I don't care what kind of dog he is
我管他什广狗
It's your dog, train it yourself
自己的狗自己牵回去教啦
Geta, nowadays the Grey Wolf's gang
Geta 灰狼这钳的
is doing very well
现在算是很威风的吗
Boss Masa, please stop teasing me
Masa大仔 你不要挖苦我了好呆
Did I say it wrong?
我说的有人错咽
Dragon, make a toast
志衣 烙酒
Boss Geta's son
Geta大仔的儿子
My son
我儿子
Dragon, handsome fellow
志龙啊 钟啶
Bro. Grey Wolf
灰狼哥
Grey Wolf, he's the most promising among
灰狼 现在在我们艇解少年措的
the younger generation in Monga
算这个最感风了
We should watch our back
我们要小心时
or soon we'll be history
不然一下子就会被弄掉了
Boss Geta, look
Geta大他 来
For the past 3 years when I was in there
我在里面这三年
thanks for taking care of our boss
站感谢你替我照顾我们老大
And people in my household
还有我家里面的人
One day I, Wim-Kian
我文训如果有机会
will do my best to repay you
一定好好报答你
Now that you're out, you should be happy
既然出来了 就要娄欢喜喜
Saying all this nonsense is useless
就那些没有意义的 没什夭用
Alright, come on, drink up
来来来 喝啦喝 来吗
Here, everyone, cheers
来 大家一起来吧
Cheers, everyone, drink up
求 大家喝 来
Cheers
来
How's your boss doing overseas?
你们老大现在在国外身体好吗
He's in good shape physically, but he's kind of depressed
身体是不错啦 就是心情攀辛啦
It's hard not to get depressed
殉让是难免的啦
Mainlanders are indeed different
外省的就是不一样
That Grey Wolf, he moves a finger and the cigarette comes
刚才那个灰狼手一伸英就来
The glass gets refilled as soon as it got empty
酒杯空了马上就倒满
It's like they were telepathic
就像是有心志感应
And the whole group
而且和后面一大堆人
stood still in the back all night long
每个人都站了一整晚
Tall and straight like the Military Police
纵意兵一样挎
My legs got sore by just looking at them
我看到腿都酸了
Sigh, Monga is hopeless
唉 艇解输了叭
join them if you like them so much
你乾脆去加入他们好了
You shitting me?
你在器天啶
They just look more impressive
他们看起来就是比较威风啊
Wouldn't we look cool if we act like them?
我们如果中他们一样不是很局里
I think they look phony
我觉得他们那样很假
Yeah, bunch of fakes
就是啊 装模作样
You know that Grey Wolf?
你是认讷那个灰狼呆
You know him personally?
你认识他
No, my mom does
没有啊 是我妈认误
Your mom's sleeping with him?
你妈味他有一腿哩
Fuck, shut your face
干 你不要妃说好不好
Ah-ha, something fishy here
吗 有龟
If your mom doesn't want him
你妈不要送我妈好了
give him to my mom. He is her type.
我妈很哈那一型的吗
Shut up
右天吗
Is it good?
好吃吗
Hmn, it's good
咽 好吃
Then I'll bring some more next time
好吃下次再带给你吃
OK
好啊
Did you have a tough time in the mountains?
你在山上很车吗
What's up with you?
你怎麻了
You look not yourself today
你看起来怪怪的耶
l ran into someone I don't like
今天看到一个诗悦的人
Who was it?
谁啊
My mom's ex, before she married my dad
我怒结婚前的男朋友
My mom said she'd been with him since she was 16
我妈说她十六成就中了他
But one day
可是后来有一天
He left without a word
他什夭都没说就委下我妈跑了
And disappeared until a few years ago
一直到绑年前才又出现
Are you gonna disappear like him someday?
你会不会跟他一样
You're scared that I'll disappear?
你以我不见啊
Silly
白疼
Why call me silly
干咏思我白狐
I won't
不会啦
What did you say?
你刚说什广
Something nice that I'm not gonna say again
好话不说第二遍
Hey boss, a barbequed chicken leg
老冉 一根烧难腿
OK, OK, right away
好好好 马上好
I'll get one more then
再帮我加一根好了
OK OK
好好
Boss, have a chicken leg
大仔 吃灯腿啊
Oh
喧
You grew up without a father?
你是没和爸爸的小孩吗
That obvious?
看得出来叶
Leave us; kids shouldn't listen to adults' discussion
你先走 大人讲话小孩不要骸
OK
好
Boss Masa
Masa大仔
l heard you've been working
册说你最近中外省的合作
Who is talking such nonsense?
你是贩纵在妃讲
Words spread fast
外面风声啊
Gimme a break
你也拜旗一下
I can't even speak Mandarin
我就速国语都说不好
how do I work with the Mainlanders?
要球外省的合作什么叭
You really buy that shit?
列人随便说说你也信
Seriously, no?
站的没有
They did talk to me about it
谈是有在谈叭
But I haven't agreed
不过我又膛没答应
That means yes then, and you're still playin' dumb with me?
这样就是有啊 你还在装俊
If Boss Geta doesn't agree
如果没跟你Geta大仔讲好
then I won't do it
我也不会去做啦
Our Monga is an old town
我们艇筋是老角枯
We have our own way and traditions in managing this place
我们有我们自己
We don't want to work with outsiders
我们不想跟列人合作
Masa and I are no exception
我跟Masa不能破这个例
l understand
这我了解
How about this?
我们这样好不好
In the beginning I won't show up
一开始我都不要出面
And you two bosses still handle everything
一切还是由十位老大处理
We can observe each other for a while
我们可以先互相观察一段时间
Until we've reached certain level of understanding and trust
等到彼此的默契跟信任度都钩了
Then we'll go from there
我们再往下走
Moreover
还有
The business I run outside of Monga
我在外面的生意
If you are interested, please let me know
十位老大如果有内趣亿管开口
I would love to have you join me
我网迎你们加入
Thanks a lot
多谢啦
I think we better stay in Monga
我想我们富在秀解
with our small business
做一些小生意就可以
We don't know much about the outside world
外面的事情我们又不懂
We are not interested in running around
不想在外面到处跑
What about Boss Masa, what do you think?
那Masa大仔的意见呢
My position is very simple
我立场很简单叭
Whatever Boss Geta says
Geta 大仔怎麻说
I do my best to follow suit
我就偿量照他的意思配合
Yeah, you are the shit now
妆 你们现在很刷
Dozens of block bosses, with losts of grease to go around
做十个角头 障容坚强 他杂油水又多
And then
然后更
Fucking old asses getting in your way
老屁股揽在前面嘛
Look at your bosses:
你看你们老大
drink all day, the women, a great life
每天他杂喝酒玩女人
Eventually, they will suck Monga dry
艇和解儿有一天被他们玩垮
It's such a wonderful land, what a waste
明明是这魔好的一据地方
Look at our Big Boss
你看看我们霸子
He's got brains
他那个脑袋
He doesn't sleep, he spends his days thinking
笋他他妈每天不睡都在想啊
Thinking about how to develop the organization
想组织要怎广发展
Now, as soon as he gives an order, it'll be like cell division
他现在一声令下细胞分裂
We'll no longer be just a gang of hundreds
我们马上就不是做百个人的才派
But tens of thousands, I am telling you
是做菌个人啊我跟你说
Guns will be brought in by sea in boxes
检一箱一箱从海上运进来
Halls will be established one after another
堂口一个一个的开
And you
你啊
Hanging out on your block
在你的角头他杂的
Selling toilet paper and selected tea, collecting fees
详本生纸实高山茶收保护费
Getting turned in every now and then
动不动就被前进去踊
Times are changing, bro
时代不一样了 兄弟
Do it right
好好搞
We set up a hall in Monga, and you'll be the Boss
盘解并一个堂 你就是堂主
Each of us needs our own stage
我们都要有舞台嘛
The world is going to be ours
以后天下是我们的
It's gonna be difficult if there's only one hall for the entire Monga
艇筋只有一个堂 有困难
The two major powers in Monga
艇和解现在最大的两个势力
Are our Back Alley and the Temple Front
就是我们和后辟导和遍口
We've got our own blocks on each side
我们各有各的角头在挺
You won't have any problem with me
我这下当然没问题
But if you wanna make this work
但如果你这局想要成
You'll have to include the Temple Front
一定要把亢口拉进来
Otherwise you'll have to deal with all the blocks behind them
要不然你光是
It won't be easy
没那广好哺
It's gonna be a tough fight
会是一场硬侈
You got someone from the Temple Front?
遍口那选有人还吗
I still remember four years ago, right here
四年前 我记得在这祷
You were against over a dozen from Da Dao Cheng
大稻埋十几个打你一个
I saw them beating the life out of you
看你叙笠要被打死了
Still you wouldn't give in
你有还是不青认输
l owe you for that
那次昌的很谢误你
No need to thank me
不用味我道谢
It was because you've got balls
是你有种
If you weren't tough enough
你如果不是个狠角色
Even if you got beaten to death in front of me 100 times
就算查我面前被打死一百遍
I wouldn't give a shit
我速看也不会看你一限
Really, 1 owe you a lot
我览的欠你很多
And that thing about the Dog Boy
还有狗仔孩的事情
lam fully aware
这件事情我很清楚
Dragon messed with somebody's girlfriend four years ago
四年前碰人家女友的是志能
But you took on the heat
不过是你出来打的
Can we spare Dragon?
可不可以不要动到志衣
What? You want to protect your brother?
怎样 你想要保你兄弟哩
Look
我球你训
lam afraid that we are losing the entire Monga
现在整个艇解都要保不住了
you know that?
你知道呆
It's like the last years of Ching Dynasty
在满清末年
All the foreign powers have surrounded China with
外国人本 枪
their firearms, canons and ships
军盘都等在外
That old empress Tz'u-Hsi still thought she could bring them all down
那个感禧还以扁自己很行
That's exactly what's happening in Monga
现在我们艇解的情况一模一样
Our Boss Masa
我们大仔Masa
puts on fancy clothes and fools around everyday
每天穿得光鲜亮娃上茶室
And your Boss Geta is a stubbern old fool
你们Geta胶袋装水泥
The future is knocking on the door, and Monga is still asleep
未来就要求了耶 艇筋人膛在睡
They all call me mad dog
大家都轧我是首狗
They are right
没错
But I had been thinking a lot during the 3 years in prison
但我在里面关了三年 也想了很多
My boss turned me in during the Big Crackdown
一清抬黑 我大他把我交出去
That Dragon, you took on the beating
那个志龙 他要是捅可子
every time he screwed up
你就要被打个半死
That's the kind of fate for people like us
这就是我们这种人的命有运
Now the Mainlanders are asking nicely to do business with us
现在外省玫很客所的要求合作
The proud old folks refused right on the spot
老一草很印 说不要就不要
When the time comes, who's put on the frontline?
到时打起来谁打
No one else but you and me
不就是你和我
It's guns in their hands
人家拿的是检敢
You really think you can fight them with a stabbing tube?
你以高征管就能中人输赢啊
Don't feel ashamed to work with the outsiders
不要认遍跟别人合作很丢脸
You really think I'll let
你以高我贤的会
the Mainlanders take over Monga?
让外省帮求我们艇筋插旗咽
Look who's thinking for Monga
今天维才是扁艇和解著想
Holy crap, all that wind, and now the rain
你娘啊 一下刮风 一下下十
Is the typhoon really coming?
且风站的要来了叶
Boss Masa have a good night, come again
Masa大他慢走 有空再来虽
And you, don't run around, be good
你不要妃跑 要冬喔
Ah, you came for Auntie Ai as well?
你也来给爱十姨捧场虽
Boss
大体
Boss Geta is here with all of his Temple Front
Geta大和合带他们遍口所有的人
brothers, to pay their respect
来给你上香
Please bless them, so that they are safe, healthy and prosperous
你要保佑他们平安健康发大财哩
Homeboy, rest in peace
兄弟 你放心去
l swear right here, on my name
我Geta在你过前发所
That I will find the murderer
一定会找出听手
To do your vengeance
高你报仇
My condolence, take care
你要和节误 要保重
Boss Geta
Geta大他
I have mobilized everyone in the Back Alley
我们后忌技已经全部动员了
I've also notified Taoyuan, Chungli and the South
桃园 中振 南部我也已经通知了
Boss, if you can help us find him
大仔你如果帮忙找人
I'd very much appreciate
我文襄非常感谢
We have to get A-Chung
反正阿患一定要抓到
l want him kneel in front of our boss, and pay back with his life
我要他跷在我老大二前 用命来还
I'll help you find A-Chung
阿忠我会帮忙找
But we don't need to kill him
但是 不一定要他的命
I'll find out if he's the murderer
泡手是不是阿忠 我会查清楚
Who knows? Maybe it's your own man
说不定是你们后壁层的自己做的
who did this, then frame him
把界证融给他
Boss, how can you say this?
大仔 你这样说不对吧
Are you saying that
你现在的意思是议
our men killed our own boss?
后壁技的小弟干掉自己老大
Fuck, I'd say someone from you Temple Front killed him
干 说不定是你们扁口狗的
Don't move!
全都不要动
God is watching, we all know what we did
人在做天在看 大家心里有数
Boss, got news from the Back Alley
大他 和后壁导的发消息
They said A-Chung is spotted nearby the Watergate
说有人看到阿忠在水门那
Now they and the Da Dao Cheng people are all out to get him
现碍跟大稳理一起去抓人了
Boss
大体
l heard A-Chung is around Watergate
匠说阿忠在水门
Everyone, go get him now
大家快去帮忙找
OK let's go
好 走吧
You go with them
你也去啊
Boss, what about you?
大仔 那你呢
There's nothing to worry about, I'm on my own turf
不要紧啦 在自己角头怕什条
Go, hurry
快去啦
Boss, you're closing
老问 你要收唆
Yeah
兰啊
Everybody's out to get A-Chung, not much business around here
大家都去水门塔阿忠 没生意好做
All of the Temple Front went?
裔口的全部都去了吗
Your Boss Geta, I think he stayed
你们Geta大他好像没去吗
Then please make two for me
那帮我烧两根好不好
Please
拜旗只
OK
好
Sorry, come early tomorrow
歹势啦 明天早蜗来
We came all the way from the South, can we just do a brief prayer?
我们南部来的耶 引我们拜一下叭
Oh
喧
Boss, boss
大仔 大仔
Anybody?
有没有人
Anybody here?
有没有人啊
Call the ambulance
叫救纺车啊
Hurry call the ambulance
快叫救访车啊
Boss
大体
Somebody?
有没有令
Call the ambulance
叫救纺车啊
Anybody here?
有没有人啊
Boss Dragon is gone
志龙大仔不见了
I told Dragon not to come today
是我叫志龙今天不要出现
If Dragon shows up today, he will die
如果今天志龙出现就一定会死
Those bastards want our Dragon dead
那些畜牧就是要我们志龙死
They want us dead
他们就是要我们死
they want us at the Temple Front all dead
要我们遍口的全死光叭
Can't you see what's happening?
这样你们还看不懂
I'll go find him
我去找他
You stay right here
你不要去
I don't want him back, I don't want him here
我不要他回来 我不要他回来
Don't you go get him
你不要把他找回来啦
our Geta will understand
我们Geta会这解 你不要
Madam, madam, calm down, have a seat
先坐下再讲只
I don't want him back
我不要他回来啦
don't bring him back
不要叫他回来啦
Who is it?
是维
It's me, me
是我 是我
It's OK now
没事了
It's me
是我
It's time, can't wait anymore
时辰到了 不能再等了
I'll do it
我来
Geta or Masa, take your pick
Geta Masa 你选一个
Geta
Geta
Goddamn sons of bitches
你们这些猴死贺仔
How dare you, getting all despicable in front of Master God
竞敢碍祖师繁面前避张
You two go from the back door
你多从和后门走
Go now
快走
If you don't kill them today
今天如果你不弄死他们
One day they'll kill you
有一天你就会被他们和弄死
l want them to pay with their blood
我要他们血债血膛
Why are you pushing me?
你高什么要逼我啊
Motherfucker
干你娘的
You think we're their match?
不自量力报什么仇啊
How on Earth do you think we can do anything about it?
你以高我们能报什舟仇
Boss Geta is dead, Boss Masa is dead too
Geta大仔死了 Masa大仔死了
Aren't you humans?
你们是不是人啊
Don't you have any feelings?
你们有没有感觉啊
Don't you be stirring things up
你少在那跟炉风串火
Everybody knows it, but no one dares to touch him
谁都知道 谁也没人敢动他
Motherfucker
干你娘
No! Stop it!
不要 不要叭
Monk
和尚
Stop it, Monk
不要啦 和尚
Stop it
列打了
At this point, revenge is suicide
现在报仇 死路一休
Besides, Dragon can't stay in Monga
而且志龙不能留在纯解
You three
你们三个
take Dragon to the Philippines, lay low for a while
带志龙去菲律宾避避风头
I'll stay and investigate
我留下来调查
I'll stay too
我也留下来
Do you remember, the night Boss Geta died
你膛记不记得Geta大仔死的那一天
You were all sent to find that A-Chung
你多都被叫去找那个阿忠
Have you ever thought
你有没有想过那个消息
it could just be a smoke bomb?
很可能只是粳园弹
A-Shing
阿殿
The thing, I want it done tomorrow
那件事情你明天要给我处理好哩
OK, no problem, leave it to me
好啦 没问题啦 交给我啦
Get some rest Boss, I'm heading off
大仔早蜗睡吗 先走唆
Monkey is involved in an armed assault
你们侯春生持拒伤人
Now the police suspects that
现在我们警方怀疑
the gun in his possesion
他拿的那把枪
is the same one that killed
般死后壁层老大张顺发的检
the Back Alley boss
是同一支
You pathetic liars
匠你在放屁
My Monkey is still at school
我们春生在学校读书有还没回来
What did you take me here for?
你们带我来这要做什广
I gotta hurry home
我要运快回去者伍
and cook for him
给我们春生吃哗
Fuck your sorry ass
我干你娘啊
Dragon, don't do that
志龙 别人这样啦
Ignore 'em
不要理他们叭
Why are they like this?
他们高什么要这样
Because Monkey killed Boss Masa
因扁白猴儿了Masa大仔啊
Apparently Boss Geta ordered Monkey to do it
这很显然是Geta大和合
so he could take over the Back Alley
高了供奉后辟层而叫白猴做的
Then they in turn killed Boss Geta and Blackie
然后他们再干掉Geta大仔跟黑面
Temple Front did something like this
今天遍口做出这种事情
The gang has lost people's respect
已经得不到大家的尊数了
What are you talking about?
你在说什麻
Monkey didn't kill Boss Masa
Masa大仔不是白猴角的
Then you go explain to everybody
那你去跟大家解释啊
What is the reason that made
今天白猴变成蔡死鬼的
Monkey become the scapegoat?
监正原因是什么
Something to drink?
喝什入
lam just here to ask you a question
我只是来问你一件事
Then I'm out of here
问完我就走
Have a seat
坐啊
Why did you leave my mom in the first place?
当初扁什么丢下我二就走
Something went wrong
因扁出事了
Had to get away
跑路
Then why didn't you explain to her?
那高什么一名话都没说
Because then she would have waited for me
我说了 她就会等
Didn't want her to waste her youth waiting
我不想耽误她的青春
Then, if you were given a second chance
那如果再给你一次机会
Would you stay with her?
你会留在她身跟呆
We only live once
人生只有一次
I've run out of my chances
我没有机会了
Yes
有
You still have a chance
你还有机会
If something happens to me, please take good care of her
如果我出事 请你好好照顾她
What are you talking about?
你说什入你
I'm warning you
我警告你虽
Your mom went through hell to raise you
你妈辛辛苦苦把你头大
You owe her your life
你这休命是她的不是你的
You get me?
你知不知道啊
But Boss Geta died in my arms
可是Geta大仔是死在我怀里的
You know what?
你知道呆
Whichever way the wind blows
风往哪个方向吹
The grass bends along
草就要往哪个方向倒
When I was young I thought I was the wind
年轻的时候
But eventually it cost me dearly
可是最后遍体鳞伤
Then I realized we're all just grass
我才知道我们原来都只是草
You are still young, you've got options
你膛年轻 还有还择
Go to the Philippines and lay low for a while
去菲律宾避避风头吧
What's gonna happen in Monga nobody knows
艇和解接下来
I need to speak to Monk
找和尚
I've made up my mind, I'll go to the Philippines too
我决定了 我也去菲律袖
I'll be in the Philippines for a couple months
我会去菲律宾做个月
You haven't served in the military, how do you get out of the country?
你又没当兵 怎麻出国
I will be back soon
我很快就会回来
I've asked Auntie how much you owe her
我有问阿姨你久了多少鲁
l'll figure out a way to get that money
这笔缕我会想闪法
When I come back
等我回来
I'll get you out of here
我一定会带你苑并这祷
I'll take you to the movies some time
找一天我带你去看电影
How's that possible
怎度可能
If 1 get caught, they'll break my legs
出去被抓回来 就是打断腿
Auntie promised me, personally
阿姨厅口答应我
She'll tell them that you're going for abortion
她会跟大家说你是去打胎
Here
来
Grey Wolf, that's it then, we're heading off
灰狼 不然这样 我们先走
Sure
好啊 好
Scar, see them to the door
刀郊 你帮我送一下
Yes, sir
是
There's no problem right?
没问题吧
Don't worry
你放心
You need to do it nice and clean
做事要做得完整
Don't leave behind anything that'd make us lose sleep
不要和弄到我们两个回响都睡不好
He already agreed to get on the boat with them
他已经答应味他们一起上船了
And then, what are we gonna do when he's back?
接下来啊 等他回来要怎广闪
Mom, I left some savings in your closet
妈 我存一蜗仅放你李子里喧
Why in my closet?
放我那里干嘛
Deposit it in the bank, and you can earn interest
拿去象行存啊 还可以生利息
Then you do it for me
那你帮我存
Boss Geta, excuse me, please lend me your 2-feet
Geta大他 歹势 借你的尺二用一下
Bless me, and help me to find the truth
请你保佑我查出事情的瘟相
Boy, go get the car
阿弟仔 去把车开过来
I'm leaving everything to you
一切麻烦你嗓
OK, take care
嗯 保重
Let's go yeah?
走吧 咽
Wait
等一下
Let's go pray to the Master God for a sec
我们四个去上柱香吧
What you talking this shit to me for?
你味我哈拉这个干嘛
I'm afraid you won't be able to explain to Sister Ling
我怕你没办法跟小玲姐交代
Explain to whom?
于维交代
I'm a goddamn gangster, who am I answering to?
我他妈出求混的跟维交代啊
He's not my son for God's sake
他又不是我儿子
Get the car; we're going to Monga
去开车 我们去盘解一趟
He's not here
不在耶
Oh, earlier he told me to deposit money for him
啊 他今天有叫我帮他存仅
What's up with all this money?
这麻多仅 怎麻回事啊
All his regular clothes are gone
常穿的衣服都不见了
Why is the postcard I sent you
高什么我寄给你的明信片
in Yi Mong's closet?
会在以文的衣摄里
How could you keep me in the dark for so many years?
你怎广可以眶我那广多年啊
Shut the door, go shut the door
把门关起来 去把门关起来
What are you doing?
你这样是在干嘛
Yeah, Mosquito, what you doing?
当啊 蚊子你在干嘛
Stay where you are
你们不要遇来
l want to know something
我想弄清楚一些事
Tell us
说清楚
Are you sending us to the boat
今天晚上是要送我们上船
or to Hell?
膛是要送我们去死
What the fuck?
件度只
There is no boat, right?
报本没有船圣不大
Mosquito, can you put down the knife first?
玉子 你可不可以把刀先放下来
If there's a misunderstanding, we can sort it out
有什夭误会大家当面说清楚嘛
There's no misunderstanding
没有误会
Listen
我球你们说
Tonight, there is no boat but trap
今天根本没有船 只有局
Thre's no way we're getting to the Philippines
我们三个不可能到得了菲律袖
Monk
和尚
Explain, what's going on?
你说清楚吗
What's the deal?
到庶怎麻回事
Why did Mosquito say something like that?
高什条蚊子会说这种话
What's the situation?
现在是什么情形
Mosquito, have you lost your mind?
玉子 你是不是瘦啦
Say it!
你说啊你
We swore to be brothers, at the very same place
我们五个曾经在这和里结拜
And now one of you's putting a knife against my neck
今天你们一个拿刀架在我脖子上
Another one is starting to doubt me
另外一个也开始怀疑我
What the fuck is this?
这算什庆啊
If you've go the fucking guts, tell the truth in front of the Master God
你他妈有种在祖师繁面前说站话
If 1 misunderstood you
今天如果是我误会你
feel free to give me a stab
捅我一刀没关傈
But if you are the traitor who sold out the Temple Front
可是如果间的是你出实遍口
l want you to pay with your life
我要你拿你的命来还
Sell out?
出实
How could that be Monk?
和尚怎广可能啊
Can you please stop this shit? OK?
你们不要盖了好不好
Stop acting like this
可不可以不要这样子
I saw him with Wim-Kian
我朵眼看到他引文吝
and Grey Wolf, with my own eyes
还有灰狼在一起
Your mama
你阿娘啊
Not my day
哇 这种牌
Times are changing
时代不一样了
The outside world is changing
外面的世界正在改变
If we are as stubborn as the old bosses
我们如果吐老一草的一样死脑筋
we'll be dead sooner or later
早晚会被春掉
The entire Monga will fall into their hands
整个艇和解都会被春掉
I met with Grey Wolf and Wim-Kian, was to save Monga
我跟灰狼文廊碰 是遍了保住艇筋
To save
保住
The Temple Front
遍口
So, did you kill my dad?
那我爸是你儿的吗
You're the one who killed my dad?
我爸是你角的时
Kill them
给他们死
Motherfuckers
干你娘 网叭
Everything I do
我做的一切
is for you
都是遍了你
Have you seen Mosquito?
你有看到玉子吗
Go get everybody
把所有人叫来
Should we go take a look?
要去看看时
If you got on the boat, then we wouldn't end up like this
你上船的莫不就没事了吗
Why didn't you just get on the boat?
你高什么不上船
Why are you making me do this?
你高什么要逼我动手
Go ahead and kill me
你弄死我啊
If you don't kill me today
你今天不弄死我
I will kill you tomorrow
明天就会被我弄死
I never understood
我从以前就不懂
what's the point in all this fighting
扁什么要人这样打打必角
Now I am even more confused
今天我更不懂
You're my brother
高什么你明明是我兄弟
but I have to kill you
我全要弄死你
Because this is the street
因遍这和里是黑道
Because we're gangsters
因扁我们混的是黑道
Whoever gets in the way dies
描路者死
There's no other choice
谁还有得膛啊
If this were the way of the street
如果黑道是这样
Then I am not a gangster
那我混的不是黑道
lam in this for friendship
我混的是友情
Guns are weapons for the lowly
枪 是下等人用的武器
Monk
和尚
You thought I was going to embrace you
刚刚你以高我要抱你
So you opened your arms
所以你张并了手
At that moment
查那一刻
You chose to believe in me, didn't you?
你还择相信了我 不是时
You thought you were in this as a gangster
你以高你混的是黑道
But like me, you're here for friendship and brotherhood, too
你混的其实也是友情 是义气
You thought Geta was a decent man?
你以高Geta是什广好东西
He wanted to become the Boss
当年他遍了上位
So he chopped off my dad's arm
斯了我爸的手
Did you know how he treated his brothers?
他是怎广兰待兄弟的 你知道里
What's good in the cinema lately?
最近有什么电影好看啊
Dumb Recruit is pretty funny
大头兵灾好笑的啊
Really
是喔
Mosquito, are you OK?
玉子 你有怎样吧
Dragon, Dragon
志衣 志允
Hurry, let's go
走啦 快走啦
Dragon
志龙
Look, something happened
出事了 匠好
Go look for some guy called Mosquito
你们运快去找一个叫归子的
Where's my ear?
我的耳朵呢
Some say
有人襄
Joining the gang is like getting a bad lot
踏入黑道 就像抽到一枝壕疆
You end up either living in exile
最后不是亡命天涯
Or getting brutally murdered on the streets
就是惨死街头
But that year, me and my brothers
可是那一年 我跟我的兄弟们
we all believed joining the gang
都认高踏入黑道
using violence to gain control
以暴治暴
was the way to rule
才是王道
The only way for survival
才是唯一的 生存之道
Why do the four of you want to recruit me?
你们四个高什么要找我加入
Because it takes five fingers
因扁五根手指合起来
to form a fist
才是一个源头